[
  {
    "question": "Google was founded by Larry Page and who else?",
    "answer1": "Steve Jobs",
    "answer2": "Sergey Brin",
    "answer3": "Bill Gates",
    "answer4": "Terry Winograd",
    "correctAnswer": "answer2",
    "answerExplanation": "Google was founded by Larry Page and Sergey Brin!"
  },
  {
    "question": "The name \"Google\" originated from a misspelling of which word?",
    "answer1": "Googol",
    "answer2": "Goosearch",
    "answer3": "Googad",
    "answer4": "Goolink",
    "correctAnswer": "answer1",
    "answerExplanation": "The name \"Google\" originated from a misspelling of Googol."
  },
  {
    "question": "Before Google, there was a search engine named what?",
    "answer1": "BackLinks",
    "answer2": "BackRub",
    "answer3": "BreakUp",
    "answer4": "BackUp",
    "correctAnswer": "answer2",
    "answerExplanation": "The search engine competition was named BackRub."
  },
  {
    "question": "The domain name www.google.com was registered on what date?",
    "answer1": "January 12, 1998",
    "answer2": "September 15, 1997",
    "answer3": "August 7, 1997",
    "answer4": "September 7, 1996",
    "correctAnswer": "answer2",
    "answerExplanation": "www.google.com was registerd on September 15, 1997."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many searches was Google querying a day in 1998?",
    "answer1": "30,000",
    "answer2": "450,000",
    "answer3": "100,000",
    "answer4": "10,000",
    "correctAnswer": "answer4",
    "answerExplanation": "They were already answering 10,000 searches a day (in 1998!)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the year 2000, Google began selling what?",
    "answer1": "Hardware",
    "answer2": "Image-based advertisements",
    "answer3": "Text-based advertisements",
    "answer4": "A keyword database",
    "correctAnswer": "answer3",
    "answerExplanation": "In 2000, Google started selling text-based advertisements based on keywords users searched."
  },
  {
    "question": "Google's search technology is nicknamed PageRank, named after who or what?",
    "answer1": "Sergey's Dog",
    "answer2": "The original homepage",
    "answer3": "A founder's girlfriend",
    "answer4": "Co-founder Larry Page",
    "correctAnswer": "answer4",
    "answerExplanation": "PageRank is named after Google's co-founder Larry Page."
  },
  {
    "question": "Google's informal corporate motto is:",
    "answer1": "Turning the Page",
    "answer2": "Always First",
    "answer3": "Don't Be Evil",
    "answer4": "Experience the Difference",
    "correctAnswer": "answer3",
    "answerExplanation": "Google's informal corporate motto is \"Don't be Evil.\""
  },
  {
    "question": "How much money did Google's first investor give the company?",
    "answer1": "$200,000",
    "answer2": "$150,000",
    "answer3": "$100,000",
    "answer4": "$400,000",
    "correctAnswer": "answer3",
    "answerExplanation": "Google's first funding received was worth $100,000."
  },
  {
    "question": "Google bought an existing startup maps company, which was named:",
    "answer1": "FindIT Tech",
    "answer2": "Where 2 Technologies",
    "answer3": "MapIT Technologies",
    "answer4": "Get Lost Technologies",
    "correctAnswer": "answer2",
    "answerExplanation": "The company was named Where 2 Technologies. It was bought in 2005."
  }
]
